<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>

  <item>
      <title>
          Replication Timing Becomes Intertwined with 3D Genome Organization</title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(19)30090-X]]></link>
      <description>
          <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/cell-press.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Jian Ma, Zhijun Duan</p>
              <p style="font-family:verdana;">Through dissecting the link between spatial genome organization and DNA replication timing, Sima et al. (2018) discover early replicating control elements (ERCEs), a new type of cis-acting elements that regulate replication timing, transcription, and multiple layers of three-dimensional features of genome organization. The study has important implications for unraveling control elements of high-order genome structure and function.</p>
          ]]></description>
      <pubDate>7 Feb 2019</pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
      <title>
          Identifying cis Elements for Spatiotemporal Control of Mammalian DNA Replication</title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(18)31561-7#%20]]></link>
      <description>
          <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/cell-press.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Jiao Sima, Abhijit Chakraborty, Vishnu Dileep, ..., Peter Fraser, Ferhat Ay, David M. Gilbert</p>
              <p style="font-family:verdana;">The temporal order of DNA replication (replication timing [RT]) is highly coupled with genome architecture, but cis-elements regulating either remain elusive. We created a series of CRISPR-mediated deletions and inversions of a pluripotency-associated topologically associating domain (TAD) in mouse ESCs. CTCF-associated domain boundaries were dispensable for RT. CTCF protein depletion weakened most TAD boundaries but had no effect on RT or A/B compartmentalization genome-wide. By contrast, deletion of three intra-TAD CTCF-independent 3D contact sites caused a domain-wide early-to-late RT shift, an A-to-B compartment switch, weakening of TAD architecture, and loss of transcription.</p>
          ]]></description>
      <pubDate>27 Dec 2018</pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
  <title>
      CRISPR-Mediated Programmable 3D Genome Positioning and Nuclear Organization</title>
  <link><![CDATA[https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0092867418311851]]></link>
  <description>
      <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/cell-press.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Haifeng Wang, Xiaoshu Xu, Cindy M. Nguyen, Yanxia Liu, Yuchen Gao, Xueqiu Lin, Timothy Daley, Nathan H. Kipniss, Marie La Russa, Lei S. Qi</p>
          <p style="font-family:verdana;">Programmable control of spatial genome organization is a powerful approach for studying how nuclear structure affects gene regulation and cellular function. Here, we develop a versatile CRISPR-genome organization (CRISPR-GO) system that can efficiently control the spatial positioning of genomic loci relative to specific nuclear compartments, including the nuclear periphery, Cajal bodies, and promyelocytic leukemia (PML) bodies. CRISPR-GO is chemically inducible and reversible, enabling interrogation of real-time dynamics of chromatin interactions with nuclear compartments in living cells.</p>
      ]]></description>
  <pubDate>15 Nov 2018</pubDate>
</item>
  
  <item>
      <title>
          Disease-Associated Short Tandem Repeats Co-localize with Chromatin Domain Boundaries</title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0092867418310213?via%3Dihub]]></link>
      <description>
          <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/cell-press.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">James H. Sun, Linda Zhou, Daniel J. Emerson, Sai A. Phyo, Katelyn R. Titus, Wanfeng Gong, Thomas G. Gilgenast, Jonathan A. Beagan, Beverly L. Davidson, Flora Tasson, Jennifer E. Phillips-Cremins</p>
              <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">More than 25 inherited human disorders are caused by the unstable expansion of repetitive DNA sequences termed short tandem repeats (STRs). A fundamental unresolved question is why some STRs are susceptible to pathologic expansion, whereas thousands of repeat tracts across the human genome are relatively stable. Here, we discover that nearly all disease-associated STRs (daSTRs) are located at boundaries demarcating 3D chromatin domains. We identify a subset of boundaries with markedly higher CpG island density compared to the rest of the genome.</p>
          ]]></description>
      <pubDate>20 Sep 2018</pubDate>
  </item>
  
</channel>
</rss>



