<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Pre-prints</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_pre_prints.xml"><img src="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>http://www.4dnucleome.org</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome pre-prints</description>



 <item>
	  <title>
		  Using three-dimensional regulatory chromatin interactions from adult and fetal cortex to interpret genetic results for psychiatric disorders and cognitive traits</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://doi.org/10.1101/406330]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Paola Giusti-Rodríguez, Leina Lu, Yuchen Yang, Cheynna A Crowley, Xiaoxiao Liu, Ivan Juric, Joshua S Martin, Armen Abnousi, S. Colby Allred, NaEshia Ancalade, Nicholas J Bray, Gerome Breen, Julien Bryois, Cynthia M Bulik, James J Crowley, Jerry Guintivano, Philip R Jansen, George J Jurjus, Yan Li, Gouri Mahajan, Sarah Marzi, Jonathan Mill, Michael C O’Donovan, James C Overholser, Michael J Owen, Antonio F Pardiñas, Sirisha Pochareddy, Danielle Posthuma, Grazyna Rajkowska, Gabriel Santpere, Jeanne E Savage, Nenad Sestan, Yurae Shin, Craig A Stockmeier, James TR Walters, Shuyang Yao, Bipolar Disorder Working Group of the Psychiatric Genomics Consortium, Eating Disorders Working Group of the Psychiatric Genomics Consortium, Gregory E Crawford, Fulai Jin, Ming Hu, Yun Li, Patrick F Sullivan</p>
		  ]]></description>
	  <pubDate>30 Jan 2020</pubDate>
  </item>

 <item>
	  <title>
		  Probing multi-way chromatin interaction with hypergraph representation learning</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.01.22.916171]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Ruochi Zhang, Jian Ma</p>
		  ]]></description>
	  <pubDate>23 Jan 2020</pubDate>
  </item>
 
 <item>
	  <title>
		  Strong intracellular signal inactivation produces sharper and more robust signaling from cell membrane to nucleus</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.01.16.909333]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Jingwei Ma, Myan Do, Mark A. Le Gros, Charles S. Peskin, Carolyn A. Larabell, Yoichiro Mori, Samuel A. Isaacson</p>
		  ]]></description>
	  <pubDate>17 Jan 2020</pubDate>
  </item>

    <item>
	  <title>
		  Memory sequencing reveals heritable single cell gene expression programs associated with distinct cellular behaviors</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://doi.org/10.1101/379016]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Sydney M. Shaffer, Benjamin L. Emert, Raul Reyes-Hueros, Christopher Coté, Guillaume Harmange, Ann E. Sizemore, Rohit Gupte, Eduardo Torre, Abhyudai Singh, Danielle S. Bassett, Arjun Raj</p>
		  ]]></description>
	  <pubDate>21 Dec 2019</pubDate>
  </item>


    <item>
	  <title>
		  Cell cycle dynamics of lamina associated DNA</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://doi.org/10.1101/2019.12.19.881979]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Tom van Schaik, Mabel Vos, Daan Peric-Hupkes, Bas van Steensel</p>
		  ]]></description>
	  <pubDate>19 Dec 2019</pubDate>
  </item>

  

</channel>
</rss>
