<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>
  
   <item>
	  <title>
		  Trans- and cis-acting effects of Firre on epigenetic features of the inactive X chromosome</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-19879-3]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_comm.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">He Fang, Giancarlo Bonora, Jordan P. Lewandowski, Jitendra Thakur, Galina N. Filippova, Steven Henikoff, Jay Shendure, Zhijun Duan, John L. Rinn, Xinxian Deng, William S. Noble, Christine M. Disteche</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Firre encodes a lncRNA involved in nuclear organization. Here, we show that Firre RNA expressed from the active X chromosome maintains histone H3K27me3 enrichment on the inactive X chromosome (Xi) in somatic cells. This trans-acting effect involves SUZ12, reflecting interactions between Firre RNA and components of the Polycomb repressive complexes. Without Firre RNA, H3K27me3 decreases on the Xi and the Xi-perinucleolar location is disrupted, possibly due to decreased CTCF binding on the Xi. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>27 Nov 2020</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  A map of cis-regulatory elements and 3D genome structures in zebrafish</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2962-9]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Hongbo Yang, Yu Luan, Tingting Liu, Hyung Joo Lee, Li Fang, Yanli Wang, Xiaotao Wang, Bo Zhang, Qiushi Jin, Khai Chung Ang, Xiaoyun Xing, Juan Wang, Jie Xu, Fan Song, Iyyanki Sriranga, Chachrit Khunsriraksakul, Tarik Salameh, Daofeng Li, Mayank N. K. Choudhary, Jacek Topczewski, Kai Wang, Glenn S. Gerhard, Ross C. Hardison, Ting Wang, Keith C. Cheng, Feng Yue</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The zebrafish (Danio rerio) has been widely used in the study of human disease and development, and about 70% of the protein-coding genes are conserved between the two species1. However, studies in zebrafish remain constrained by the sparse annotation of functional control elements in the zebrafish genome. Here we performed RNA sequencing, assay for transposase-accessible chromatin using sequencing (ATAC-seq), chromatin immunoprecipitation with sequencing, whole-genome bisulfite sequencing, and chromosome conformation capture (Hi-C) experiments in up to eleven adult and two embryonic tissues to generate a comprehensive map of transcriptomes, cis-regulatory elements, heterochromatin, methylomes and 3D genome organization in the zebrafish Tübingen reference strain. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>25 Nov 2020</pubDate>
  </item>

     <item>
	  <title>
		  Stress-induced RNA–chromatin interactions promote endothelial dysfunction</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-18957-w]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_comm.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Riccardo Calandrelli, Lixia Xu, Yingjun Luo, Weixin Wu, Xiaochen Fan, Tri Nguyen, Chien-Ju Chen, Kiran Sriram, Xiaofang Tang, Andrew B. Burns, Rama Natarajan, Zhen Bouman Chen, Sheng Zhong</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Chromatin-associated RNA (caRNA) has been proposed as a type of epigenomic modifier. Here, we test whether environmental stress can induce cellular dysfunction through modulating RNA-chromatin interactions. We induce endothelial cell (EC) dysfunction with high glucose and TNFα (H + T), that mimic the common stress in diabetes mellitus. We characterize the H + T-induced changes in gene expression by single cell (sc)RNA-seq, DNA interactions by Hi-C, and RNA-chromatin interactions by iMARGI. [...] Taken together, caRNA-mediated dysregulation of gene expression modulates EC dysfunction, a crucial mechanism underlying numerous diseases.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>15 Oct 2020</pubDate>
  </item>
  

</channel>
</rss>



