<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>
  
   <item>
	  <title>
		  Single-cell measurement of higher-order 3D genome organization with scSPRITE</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41587-021-00998-1]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_biotech.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Mary V. Arrastia, Joanna W. Jachowicz, Noah Ollikainen, Matthew S. Curtis, Charlotte Lai, Sofia A. Quinodoz, David A. Selck, Rustem F. Ismagilov, Mitchell Guttman</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Although three-dimensional (3D) genome organization is central to many aspects of nuclear function, it has been difficult to measure at the single-cell level. To address this, we developed ‘single-cell split-pool recognition of interactions by tag extension’ (scSPRITE). scSPRITE uses split-and-pool barcoding to tag DNA fragments in the same nucleus and their 3D spatial arrangement. Because scSPRITE measures multiway DNA contacts, it generates higher-resolution maps within an individual cell than can be achieved by proximity ligation. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>23 Aug 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  HP1α is a chromatin crosslinker that controls nuclear and mitotic chromosome mechanics</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41422-021-00515-8]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/elife.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Amy R Strom, Ronald J Biggs, Edward J Banigan, Xiaotao Wang, Katherine Chiu, Cameron Herman, Jimena Collado, Feng Yue, Joan C Ritland Politz, Leah J Tait, David Scalzo, Agnes Telling, Mark Groudine, Clifford P Brangwynne, John F Marko, Andrew D Stephens</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Chromatin, which consists of DNA and associated proteins, contains genetic information and is a mechanical component of the nucleus. Heterochromatic histone methylation controls nucleus and chromosome stiffness, but the contribution of heterochromatin protein HP1α (CBX5) is unknown. We used a novel HP1α auxin-inducible degron human cell line to rapidly degrade HP1α. Degradation did not alter transcription, local chromatin compaction, or histone methylation, but did decrease chromatin stiffness. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>09 Jun 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  RNA m6A modification orchestrates a LINE-1–host interaction that facilitates retrotransposition and contributes to long gene vulnerability</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41422-021-00515-8]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/cell_research.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Feng Xiong, Ruoyu Wang, Joo-Hyung Lee, Shenglan Li, Shin-Fu Chen, Zian Liao, Lana Al Hasani, Phuoc T. Nguyen, Xiaoyu Zhu, Joanna Krakowiak, Dung-Fang Lee, Leng Han, Kuang-Lei Tsai, Ying Liu, Wenbo Li</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The molecular basis underlying the interaction between retrotransposable elements (RTEs) and the human genome remains poorly understood. Here, we profiled N6-methyladenosine (m6A) deposition on nascent RNAs in human cells by developing a new method MINT-Seq, which revealed that many classes of RTE RNAs, particularly intronic LINE-1s (L1s), are strongly methylated. These m6A-marked intronic L1s (MILs) are evolutionarily young, sense-oriented to hosting genes, and are bound by a dozen RNA binding proteins (RBPs) that are putative novel readers of m6A-modified RNAs, including a nuclear matrix protein SAFB. Notably, m6A positively controls the expression of both autonomous L1s and co-transcribed L1 relics, promoting L1 retrotransposition. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>09 Jun 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  Deep learning connects DNA traces to transcription to reveal predictive features beyond enhancer–promoter contact</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-23831-4]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_comm.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Aparna R. Rajpurkar, Leslie J. Mateo, Sedona E. Murphy, Alistair N. Boettiger</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Chromatin architecture plays an important role in gene regulation. Recent advances in super-resolution microscopy have made it possible to measure chromatin 3D structure and transcription in thousands of single cells. However, leveraging these complex data sets with a computationally unbiased method has been challenging. Here, we present a deep learning-based approach to better understand to what degree chromatin structure relates to transcriptional state of individual cells. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>08 Jun 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  Genome-wide detection of enhancer-hijacking events from chromatin interaction data in rearranged genomes</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-021-01164-w]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_methods.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Xiaotao Wang, Jie Xu, Baozhen Zhang, Ye Hou, Fan Song, Huijue Lyu, Feng Yue</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Recent efforts have shown that structural variations (SVs) can disrupt three-dimensional genome organization and induce enhancer hijacking, yet no computational tools exist to identify such events from chromatin interaction data. Here, we develop NeoLoopFinder, a computational framework to identify the chromatin interactions induced by SVs, including interchromosomal translocations, large deletions and inversions. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>03 Jun 2021</pubDate>
  </item>
  

</channel>
</rss>



