<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Pre-prints</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_pre_prints.xml"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>http://www.4dnucleome.org</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome pre-prints</description>

<item>
	  <title>
		  Three-dimensional organization of chromatin associated RNAs and their role in chromatin architecture in human cells</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.06.10.447969]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Calandrelli, R., Wen, X., Nguyen, T. C., Chen, C.-J., Qi, Z., Chen, W., Yan, Z., Wu, W., Zaleta-Rivera, K., Hu, R., Yu, M., Wang, Y., Ma, J., Ren, B., Zhong, S.</p>
		  ]]></description>
	  <pubDate>11 Jun 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
	  <title>
		  Systematic reconstruction of the cellular trajectories of mammalian embryogenesis</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.06.08.447626]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Qiu, C., Cao, J., Li, T., Srivatsan, S., Huang, X., Calderon, D., Noble, W. S., Disteche, C. M., Spielmann, M., Moens, C. B., Trapnell, C., Shendure, J.</p>
		  ]]></description>
	  <pubDate>9 Jun 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
	  <title>
		  Micro-Meta App: an interactive software tool to facilitate the collection of microscopy metadata based on community-driven specifications</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.05.31.446382]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Rigano, A., Ehmsen, S., Ozturk, S. U., Ryan, J., Balashov, A., Hammer, M., Kirli, K., Bellve, K., Boehm, U., Brown, C. M., Chambers, J. J., Coleman, R. A., Cosolo, A., Faklaris, O., Fogarty, K., Guilbert, T., Hamacher, A. B., Itano, M. S., Keeley, D. P., Kunis, S., Lacoste, J., Laude, A., Ma, W., Marcello, M., Montero-Llopis, P., Nelson, G., Nitschke, R., Pimentel, J. A., Weidtkamp-Peters, S., Park, P. J., Alver, B., Grunwald, D., Strambio-De-Castillia, C.</p>
		  ]]></description>
	  <pubDate>31 May 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
	  <title>
		  Cell-type specialization in the brain is encoded by specific long-range chromatin topologies</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.04.02.020990v3]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Winick-Ng, W., Kukalev, A., Harabula, I., Zea Redondo, L., Meijer, M., Serebreni, L., Bianco, S., Szabo, D., Chiariello, A. M., Irastorza Azcarate, I., Fiorillo, L., Musella, F., Thieme, C., Irani, E., Torlai Triglia, E., Kolodziejczyk, A. A., Abentung, A., Apostolova, G., Paul, E. J., Franke, V., Kempfer, R., Akalin, A., Teichmann, S., Dechant, G., Ungless, M. A., Nicodemi, M., Castelo-Branco, G., Pombo, A.</p>
		  ]]></description>
	  <pubDate>12 May 2021</pubDate>
  </item>
 

</channel>
</rss>
