<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>
  

  	<item>
	  <title>
		  Developmental Pathways Are Epigenetically Reprogrammed during Lung Cancer Brain Metastasis</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://aacrjournals.org/cancerres/article-abstract/82/15/2692/707331/Developmental-Pathways-Are-Epigenetically?redirectedFrom=fulltext]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/aarc.jpeg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Jennifer A. Karlow, Siddhartha Devarakonda, Xiaoyun Xing, Hyo Sik Jang, Ramaswamy Govindan, Mark Watson, Ting Wang</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Non–small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) is one of the most commonly diagnosed and deadliest cancers worldwide, with roughly half of all patients initially presenting with both primary and metastatic disease. While the major events in the metastatic cascade have been identified, a mechanistic understanding of how NSCLC routinely and successfully colonizes the brain is largely unknown. Recent studies have begun demonstrating the role of epigenetic misregulation during tumorigenesis and metastasis, including widespread changes in DNA methylation and histone modifications. To better understand the role of altered DNA methylation in NSCLC metastasis to the brain, we measured DNA methylation during disease progression for 12 patients, globally profiling the methylation status of normal lung, primary lung tumor, and brain metastasis samples. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>03 Aug 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

  	<item>
	  <title>
		  Genome-wide CRISPR screens of T cell exhaustion identify chromatin remodeling factors that limit T cell persistence</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35750052/]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/cell-press.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Julia A Belk, Winnie Yao, Nghi Ly, Katherine A Freitas, Yan-Ting Chen, Quanming Shi, Alfredo M Valencia, Eric Shifrut, Nupura Kale, Kathryn E Yost, Connor V Duffy, Bence Daniel, Madeline A Hwee, Zhuang Miao, Alan Ashworth, Crystal L Mackall, Alexander Marson, Julia Carnevale, Santosh A Vardhana, Ansuman T Satpathy</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">T cell exhaustion limits antitumor immunity, but the molecular determinants of this process remain poorly understood. Using a chronic stimulation assay, we performed genome-wide CRISPR-Cas9 screens to systematically discover regulators of T cell exhaustion, which identified an enrichment of epigenetic factors. In vivo CRISPR screens in murine and human tumor models demonstrated that perturbation of the INO80 and BAF chromatin remodeling complexes improved T cell persistence in tumors. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>11 Jul 2022</pubDate>
  </item>
  
  	<item>
	  <title>
		  Nuclear speckles - a driving force in gene expression</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35788677/]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/journal-of-cell-science-logo_0.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Gabriel P. Faber, Shani Nadav-Eliyahu, Yaron Shav-Tal </p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">[...] As discussed in this Review, nuclear speckles represent a fascinating target of study not only to reveal the links between gene positioning, genome subcompartments and gene activity, but also as a potential target for therapeutics.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>5 Jul 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

	<item>
	  <title>
		  Integrative genome modeling platform reveals essentiality of rare contact events in 3D genome organizations</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35817938/]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_methods.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Lorenzo Boninsegna, Asli Yildirim, Guido Polles, Yuxiang Zhan, Sofia A. Quinodoz, Elizabeth H. Finn, Mitchell Guttman, Xianghong Jasmine Zhou & Frank Alber </p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">A multitude of sequencing-based and microscopy technologies provide the means to unravel the relationship between the three-dimensional organization of genomes and key regulatory processes of genome function. Here, we develop a multimodal data integration approach to produce populations of single-cell genome structures that are highly predictive for nuclear locations of genes and nuclear bodies, local chromatin compaction and spatial segregation of functionally related chromatin. [...] </p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>11 Jul 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

    <item>
	  <title>
		  Temporally dynamic antagonism between transcription and chromatin compaction controls stochastic photoreceptor specification in flies</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35835116/]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/cell-press.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Lukas Voortman, Caitlin Anderson, Elizabeth Urban, Luorongxin Yuan, Sang Tran, Alexandra Neuhaus-Follini, Josh Derrick, Thomas Gregor, Robert J.Johnston Jr. </p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Stochastic mechanisms diversify cell fates during development. How cells randomly choose between two or more fates remains poorly understood. In the Drosophila eye, the random mosaic of two R7 photoreceptor subtypes is determined by expression of the transcription factor Spineless (Ss). We investigated how cis-regulatory elements and trans factors regulate nascent transcriptional activity and chromatin compaction at the ss gene locus during R7 development. [...] </p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>12 Jul 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

      <item>
	  <title>
		  Loop-extrusion and polymer phase-separation can co-exist at the single-molecule level to shape chromatin folding</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-31856-6]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_comm.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Mattia Conte, Ehsan Irani, Andrea M. Chiariello, Alex Abraham, Simona Bianco, Andrea Esposito & Mario Nicodemi  </p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Loop-extrusion and phase-separation have been proposed as mechanisms that shape chromosome spatial organization. It is unclear, however, how they perform relative to each other in explaining chromatin architecture data and whether they compete or co-exist at the single-molecule level. Here, we compare models of polymer physics based on loop-extrusion and phase-separation, as well as models where both mechanisms act simultaneously in a single molecule, against multiplexed FISH data available in human loci in IMR90 and HCT116 cells. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>13 Jul 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

        <item>
	  <title>
		  Exploring genomic data coupled with 3D chromatin structures using the WashU Epigenome Browser</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-022-01550-y]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_methods.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Daofeng Li, Jessica K. Harrison, Deepak Purushotham & Ting Wang </p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">[...] The WashU Epigenome Browser was invented in 2011 as an interactive tool for exploring genomic data in a web browser. We have now expanded the browser functions to allow investigators to visually explore 1D, 2D and 3D genomic data on a single webpage. The key innovation is to thread the linear genomic coordinates onto a multi-resolution 3D model of the chromosome.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>21 Jul 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

          <item>
	  <title>
		  Nucleome Browser: an integrative and multimodal data navigation platform for 4D Nucleome</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-022-01559-3]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_methods.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Xiaopeng Zhu, Yang Zhang, Yuchuan Wang, Dechao Tian, Andrew S. Belmont, Jason R. Swedlow & Jian Ma</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The epigenomics community, including the NIH 4D Nucleome (4DN) Consortium, is generating numerous genomic and imaging datasets for studying nuclear structure and function. Integrating primary data with secondary analysis results will be required to create a comprehensive reference map of nuclear organization. No existing tool can effectively integrate such multimodal data for scalable and interactive visualization. Here, we introduce the Nucleome Browser (http://www.nucleome.org), an integrative and interactive multimodal data visualization and exploration platform that accelerates access, utilization and sharing of 4DN data.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>21 Jul 2022</pubDate>
  </item>
  

</channel>
</rss>



