<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>
  
  
  <item>
	  <title>
		  Three-dimensional genome restructuring across timescales of activity-induced neuronal gene expression</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41593-020-0634-6#Ack1]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_neuro.jpeg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Jonathan A. Beagan, Elissa D. Pastuzyn, Lindsey R. Fernandez, Michael H. Guo, Kelly Feng, Katelyn R. Titus, Harshini Chandrashekar, Jason D. Shepherd, Jennifer E. Phillips-Cremins</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Neuronal activation induces rapid transcription of immediate early genes (IEGs) and longer-term chromatin remodeling around secondary response genes (SRGs). Here, we use high-resolution chromosome-conformation-capture carbon-copy sequencing (5C-seq) to elucidate the extent to which long-range chromatin loops are altered during short- and long-term changes in neural activity. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>25 May 2020</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
	  <title>
		  MATCHA: Probing Multi-way Chromatin Interaction with Hypergraph Representation Learning</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.cell.com/cell-systems/fulltext/S2405-4712(20)30147-2]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/cell-press.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Ruochi Zhang, Jian Ma</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">[...] Here, we develop an algorithm called MATCHA, based on hypergraph representation learning, where multi-way chromatin interactions are represented as hyperedges. Applications to SPRITE and ChIA-Drop data suggest that MATCHA is effective to denoise the data and make de novo predictions, which greatly enhances the data quality for analyzing the properties of multi-way chromatin interactions. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>20 May 2020</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
	  <title>
		  Distinct features of nucleolus-associated domains in mouse embryonic stem cells</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00412-020-00734-9]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/springer_link.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Aizhan Bizhanova, Aimin Yan, Jun Yu, Lihua Julie Zhu, Paul D. Kaufman</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Heterochromatin in eukaryotic interphase cells frequently localizes to the nucleolar periphery (nucleolus-associated domains (NADs)) and the nuclear lamina (lamina-associated domains (LADs)). Gene expression in somatic cell NADs is generally low, but NADs have not been characterized in mammalian stem cells. Here, we generated the first genome-wide map of NADs in mouse embryonic stem cells (mESCs) via deep sequencing of chromatin associated with biochemically purified nucleoli. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>26 Mar 2020</pubDate>
  </item>
  

</channel>
</rss>



