<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>

  <item>
	  <title>
		  MAPS: Model-based analysis of long-range chromatin interactions from PLAC-seq and HiChIP experiments</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1006982]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/logo.PLOS.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Ivan Juric, Miao Yu, Armen Abnousi, Ramya Raviram, Rongxin Fang, Yuan Zhao, Yanxiao Zhang, Yunjiang Qiu, Yuchen Yang, Yun Li, Bing Ren, Ming Hu</p>
			  <p style="font-family:verdana;">Hi-C and chromatin immunoprecipitation (ChIP) have been combined to identify long-range chromatin interactions genome-wide at reduced cost and enhanced resolution, but extracting information from the resulting datasets has been challenging. Here we describe a computational method, MAPS, Model-based Analysis of PLAC-seq and HiChIP, to process the data from such experiments and identify long-range chromatin interactions.</p>
		  ]]></description>
	  <pubDate>15 Apr 2019</pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
	  <title>
		  Dynamics of genome reorganization during human cardiogenesis reveal an RBM20-dependent splicing factory</title>
	<link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-09483-5]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Alessandro Bertero, Paul A. Fields, Vijay Ramani, Giancarlo Bonora, Galip G. Yardimci, Hans Reinecke, Lil Pabon, William S. Noble, Jay Shendure & Charles E. Murry</p>
			  <p style="font-family:verdana;">Functional changes in spatial genome organization during human development are poorly understood. Here we report a comprehensive profile of nuclear dynamics during human cardiogenesis from pluripotent stem cells by integrating Hi-C, RNA-seq and ATAC-seq.</p>
		  ]]></description>
	  <pubDate>4 Apr 2019</pubDate>
  </item>
  
  
  <item>
      <title>
          Genome-wide colocalization of RNA–DNA interactions and fusion RNA pairs</title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-019-0949-1]]></link>
      <description>
          <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/pnas.jpeg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Zhangming Yan, Norman Huang, Weixin Wu, Weizhong Chen, Yiqun Jiang, Jingyao Chen, Xuerui Huang, Xingzhao Wen, Jie Xu, Qiushi Jin, Kang Zhang, Zhen Chen, Shu Chien, and Sheng Zhong</p>
              <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">It remains formidable to predict what unreported RNA pairs can form new fusion transcripts. By systematic mapping of chromatin-associated RNAs and their respective genomic interaction loci, we obtained genome-wide RNA–DNA interaction maps from two noncancerous cell types. The gene pairs involved in RNA–DNA interactions in these normal cells exhibited strong overlap with those with cancer-derived fusion transcripts.</p>
          ]]></description>
      <pubDate>19 Feb 2019</pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
      <title>
          Multiplex chromatin interactions with single-molecule precision</title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-019-0949-1]]></link>
      <description>
          <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Meizhen Zheng, Simon Zhongyuan Tian, Daniel Capurso, Minji Kim, Rahul Maurya, Byoungkoo Lee, Emaly Piecuch, Liang Gong, Jacqueline Jufen Zhu, Zhihui Li, Chee Hong Wong, Chew Yee Ngan, Ping Wang, Xiaoan Ruan, Chia-Lin Wei & Yijun Ruan</p>
              <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">[...] Here we describe a strategy for multiplex chromatin-interaction analysis via droplet-based and barcode-linked sequencing, which we name ChIA-Drop. We demonstrate the robustness of ChIA-Drop in capturing complex chromatin interactions with single-molecule precision, which has not been possible using methods based on population-level pairwise contacts.</p>
          ]]></description>
      <pubDate>18 Feb 2019</pubDate>
  </item>
  

  
</channel>
</rss>



