<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>
  
  	<item>
	  <title>
		  Uncovering the Principles of Genome Folding by 3D Chromatin Modeling</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://cshperspectives.cshlp.org/content/14/6/a039693.long]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/csh.jpeg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Asli Yildirim, Lorenzo Boninsegna, Yuxiang Zhan, Frank Alber</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Our understanding of how genomic DNA is tightly packed inside the nucleus, yet is still accessible for vital cellular processes, has grown dramatically over recent years with advances in microscopy and genomics technologies. Computational methods have played a pivotal role in the structural interpretation of experimental data, which helped unravel some organizational principles of genome folding. Here, we give an overview of current computational efforts in mechanistic and data-driven 3D chromatin structure modeling. We discuss strengths and limitations of different methods and evaluate the added value and benefits of computational approaches to infer the 3D structural and dynamic properties of the genome and its underlying mechanisms at different scales and resolution, ranging from the dynamic formation of chromatin loops and topological associated domains to nuclear compartmentalization of chromatin and nuclear bodies.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>14 June 2022</pubDate>
  </item>
  
  	<item>
	  <title>
		  TCF-1 promotes chromatin interactions across topologically associating domains in T cell progenitors</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41590-022-01232-z]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_immunol.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Wenliang Wang, Aditi Chandra, Naomi Goldman, Sora Yoon, Emily K. Ferrari, Son. C. Nguyen, Eric F. Joyce, Golnaz Vahedi </p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The high mobility group (HMG) transcription factor TCF-1 is essential for early T cell development. Although in vitro biochemical assays suggest that HMG proteins can serve as architectural elements in the assembly of higher-order nuclear organization, the contribution of TCF-1 on the control of three-dimensional (3D) genome structures during T cell development remains unknown. Here, we investigated the role of TCF-1 in 3D genome reconfiguration. Using gain- and loss-of-function experiments, we discovered that the co-occupancy of TCF-1 and the architectural protein CTCF altered the structure of topologically associating domains in T cell progenitors, leading to interactions between previously insulated regulatory elements and target genes at late stages of T cell development. The TCF-1-dependent gain in long-range interactions was linked to deposition of active enhancer mark H3K27ac and recruitment of the cohesin-loading factor NIPBL at active enhancers. These data indicate that TCF-1 has a role in controlling global genome organization during T cell development.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>20 June 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

    	<item>
	  <title>
		  The Association of MEG3 lncRNA with Nuclear Speckles in Living Cells</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.mdpi.com/2073-4409/11/12/1942]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_cell_bio.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Sarah E. Hasenson, Ella Alkalay, Mohammad K. Atrash, Alon Boocholez, Julianna Gershbaum, Hodaya Hochberg-Laufer, Yaron Shav-Tal</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Nuclear speckles are nuclear bodies containing RNA-binding proteins as well as RNAs including long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs). Maternally expressed gene 3 (MEG3) is a nuclear retained lncRNA found to associate with nuclear speckles. To understand the association dynamics of MEG3 lncRNA with nuclear speckles in living cells, we generated a fluorescently tagged MEG3 transcript that could be detected in real time. Under regular conditions, transient association of MEG3 with nuclear speckles was observed, including a nucleoplasmic fraction. Transcription or splicing inactivation conditions, known to affect nuclear speckle structure, showed prominent and increased association of MEG3 lncRNA with the nuclear speckles, specifically forming a ring-like structure around the nuclear speckles. [...] </p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>16 June 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

  

</channel>
</rss>



