<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>4DN News and Announcements</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_news.xml"><img src="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>http://www.4dnucleome.org</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome News and Announcements</description>

  <item>
	  <title>
		 Outreach activity from Prof. Zhen Chen at Cold Spring Harbor Meeting</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.4dnucleome.org/outreach.html]]></link>
	  <description>
		  Dr. Zhen Chen from City of Hope and part of 4DN OH gave a talk at Cold Spring Harbor Meeting of Mechanisms of Eukaryotic Transcription titled “Dynamic changes in RNA-chromatin interactome promotes endothelial dysfunction”. She introduced to the audience 4DN resources including 4DN protocols, datasets, and papers that are potentially useful to their research.</description>
	  <pubDate>1 Sep 2019</pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
	  <title>
		  4DN YouTube Channel</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.4dnucleome.org/outreach.html]]></link>
	  <description>
		  7 new videos of scientific webinars uploaded to the channel!</description>
	  <pubDate>1 Sep 2019</pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
	  <title>
		  4DN Directory system launched! </title><link><![CDATA[https://people.4dnucleome.org/]]></link>
	  <description>4DN OH has developed and deployed 4DN Directory, a centralized and integrated system for all 4DN personnel information where members can access the information of all 4DN members.
	  </description>
	  <pubDate>1 Sep 2019</pubDate>
  </item> 
  
  <item>
	  <title>
		  The Four-Dimensional Genome Symposium, 29 Mar - 1 Apr 2020, EMBL Heidelberg, Germany</title><link><![CDATA[https://www.embo-embl-symposia.org/symposia/2020/EES20-03/]]></link>
	  <description>This symposium will bring together latest advances in the fields of genomics, microscopy and modelling to foster their integration towards a comprehensive spatial and temporal understanding of the functional four-dimensional organisation of the eukaryotic genome.
	  </description>
	  <pubDate>17 Oct 2019</pubDate>
  </item>   
  
<item>
  <title>
	  4DN-ASCB Satellite Meeting. Capital Hilton, Washington, D.C. December 5-6, 2019</title><link><![CDATA[https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-ascb-meeting-2019.html]]></link>
  <description>LATE REGISTRATION STILL OPEN UNTIL NOVEMBER 1 (abstract submission closed). This conference, jointly organized by the 4D Nucleome (4DN) network and the American Society of Cell Biology (ASCB), will feature recent technological and conceptual advances in research of the higher order chromatin organization in eukaryotic cells.
  </description>
  <pubDate>16 Oct 2019</pubDate>
</item>


</channel>
</rss>
