<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://beta.4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>
  
     <item>
	  <title>
		  Stress-induced RNA–chromatin interactions promote endothelial dysfunction</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-18957-w]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_comm.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Riccardo Calandrelli, Lixia Xu, Yingjun Luo, Weixin Wu, Xiaochen Fan, Tri Nguyen, Chien-Ju Chen, Kiran Sriram, Xiaofang Tang, Andrew B. Burns, Rama Natarajan, Zhen Bouman Chen, Sheng Zhong</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Chromatin-associated RNA (caRNA) has been proposed as a type of epigenomic modifier. Here, we test whether environmental stress can induce cellular dysfunction through modulating RNA-chromatin interactions. We induce endothelial cell (EC) dysfunction with high glucose and TNFα (H + T), that mimic the common stress in diabetes mellitus. We characterize the H + T-induced changes in gene expression by single cell (sc)RNA-seq, DNA interactions by Hi-C, and RNA-chromatin interactions by iMARGI. [...] Taken together, caRNA-mediated dysregulation of gene expression modulates EC dysfunction, a crucial mechanism underlying numerous diseases.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>15 Oct 2020</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  Multi-contact 3C reveals that the human genome during interphase is largely not entangled</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41594-020-0506-5]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_structural_molecular.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Filipe Tavares-Cadete, Davood Norouzi, Bastiaan Dekker, Yu Liu, Job Dekker</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">During interphase, the eukaryotic genome is organized into chromosome territories that are spatially segregated into compartment domains. The extent to which interacting domains or chromosomes are entangled is not known. We analyze series of co-occurring chromatin interactions using multi-contact 3C (MC-3C) in human cells to provide insights into the topological entanglement of chromatin. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>14 Sep 2020</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  Alteration of genome folding via contact domain boundary insertion</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41588-020-0680-8]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_genetics.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Di Zhang, Peng Huang, Malini Sharma, Cheryl A. Keller, Belinda Giardine, Haoyue Zhang, Thomas G. Gilgenast, Jennifer E. Phillips-Cremins, Ross C. Hardison, Gerd A. Blobel</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Animal chromosomes are partitioned into contact domains. Pathogenic domain disruptions can result from chromosomal rearrangements or perturbation of architectural factors. However, such broad-scale alterations are insufficient to define the minimal requirements for domain formation. Moreover, to what extent domains can be engineered is just beginning to be explored. In an attempt to create contact domains, we inserted a 2-kb DNA sequence underlying a tissue-invariant domain boundary—containing a CTCF-binding site (CBS) and a transcription start site (TSS)—into 16 ectopic loci across 11 chromosomes, and characterized its architectural impact. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>31 Aug 2020</pubDate>
  </item>

     <item>
	  <title>
		  Two-Color Imaging of Non-repetitive Endogenous Loci in Human Cells</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acssynbio.0c00295]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/acs_logo.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Ipek Tasan, Christina Jean Su, Behnam Enghiad, Meng Zhang, Shekhar Mishra, Huimin Zhao</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Tools for live cell imaging of multiple non-repetitive genomic loci in mammalian cells are necessary to study chromatin dynamics. Here, we report a new system based on two chromosomally integrated orthogonal irregular repeat arrays and particularly a new general strategy to construct irregular repeat arrays. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>21 Aug 2020</pubDate>
  </item>
  

</channel>
</rss>



