<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>
  
   <item>
	  <title>
		  RNA m6A modification orchestrates a LINE-1–host interaction that facilitates retrotransposition and contributes to long gene vulnerability</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41422-021-00515-8]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/cell_research.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Feng Xiong, Ruoyu Wang, Joo-Hyung Lee, Shenglan Li, Shin-Fu Chen, Zian Liao, Lana Al Hasani, Phuoc T. Nguyen, Xiaoyu Zhu, Joanna Krakowiak, Dung-Fang Lee, Leng Han, Kuang-Lei Tsai, Ying Liu, Wenbo Li</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The molecular basis underlying the interaction between retrotransposable elements (RTEs) and the human genome remains poorly understood. Here, we profiled N6-methyladenosine (m6A) deposition on nascent RNAs in human cells by developing a new method MINT-Seq, which revealed that many classes of RTE RNAs, particularly intronic LINE-1s (L1s), are strongly methylated. These m6A-marked intronic L1s (MILs) are evolutionarily young, sense-oriented to hosting genes, and are bound by a dozen RNA binding proteins (RBPs) that are putative novel readers of m6A-modified RNAs, including a nuclear matrix protein SAFB. Notably, m6A positively controls the expression of both autonomous L1s and co-transcribed L1 relics, promoting L1 retrotransposition. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>09 June 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  Deep learning connects DNA traces to transcription to reveal predictive features beyond enhancer–promoter contact</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-23831-4]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_comm.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Aparna R. Rajpurkar, Leslie J. Mateo, Sedona E. Murphy, Alistair N. Boettiger</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Chromatin architecture plays an important role in gene regulation. Recent advances in super-resolution microscopy have made it possible to measure chromatin 3D structure and transcription in thousands of single cells. However, leveraging these complex data sets with a computationally unbiased method has been challenging. Here, we present a deep learning-based approach to better understand to what degree chromatin structure relates to transcriptional state of individual cells. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>08 June 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  Genome-wide detection of enhancer-hijacking events from chromatin interaction data in rearranged genomes</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-021-01164-w]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_methods.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Xiaotao Wang, Jie Xu, Baozhen Zhang, Ye Hou, Fan Song, Huijue Lyu, Feng Yue</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Recent efforts have shown that structural variations (SVs) can disrupt three-dimensional genome organization and induce enhancer hijacking, yet no computational tools exist to identify such events from chromatin interaction data. Here, we develop NeoLoopFinder, a computational framework to identify the chromatin interactions induced by SVs, including interchromosomal translocations, large deletions and inversions. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>03 June 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  Chromatin architecture transitions from zebrafish sperm through early embryogenesis</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://genome.cshlp.org/content/early/2021/05/18/gr.269860.120.long]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/genome_research.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Candice L. Wike, Yixuan Guo, Mengyao Tan, Ryohei Nakamura, Dana Klatt Shaw, Noelia Díaz, Aneasha F. Whittaker-Tademy, Neva C. Durand, Erez Lieberman Aiden, Juan M. Vaquerizas, David Grunwald, Hiroyuki Takeda, Bradley R. Cairns</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Chromatin architecture mapping in 3D formats has increased our understanding of how regulatory sequences and gene expression are connected and regulated in a genome. The 3D chromatin genome shows extensive remodeling during embryonic development, and although the cleavage-stage embryos of most species lack structure before zygotic genome activation (pre-ZGA), zebrafish has been reported to have structure. Here, we aimed to determine the chromosomal architecture in paternal/sperm zebrafish gamete cells to discern whether it either resembles or informs early pre-ZGA zebrafish embryo chromatin architecture. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>29 May 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

     <item>
	  <title>
		  Enhancer release and retargeting activates disease-susceptibility genes</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03577-1]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Soohwan Oh, Jiaofang Shao, Joydeep Mitra, Feng Xiong, Matteo D’Antonio, Ruoyu Wang, Ivan Garcia-Bassets, Qi Ma, Xiaoyu Zhu, Joo-Hyung Lee, Sreejith J. Nair, Feng Yang, Kenneth Ohgi, Kelly A. Frazer, Zhengdong D. Zhang, Wenbo Li, Michael G. Rosenfeld </p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The functional engagement between an enhancer and its target promoter ensures precise gene transcription1. Understanding the basis of promoter choice by enhancers has important implications for health and disease. Here we report that functional loss of a preferred promoter can release its partner enhancer to loop to and activate an alternative promoter (or alternative promoters) in the neighbourhood. We refer to this target-switching process as ‘enhancer release and retargeting’. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>26 May 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  CTCF mediates dosage- and sequence-context-dependent transcriptional insulation by forming local chromatin domains</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41588-021-00863-6]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_genetics.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Hui Huang, Quan Zhu, Adam Jussila, Yuanyuan Han, Bogdan Bintu, Colin Kern, Mattia Conte, Yanxiao Zhang, Simona Bianco, Andrea M. Chiariello, Miao Yu, Rong Hu, Melodi Tastemel, Ivan Juric, Ming Hu, Mario Nicodemi, Xiaowei Zhuang, Bing Ren</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Insulators play a critical role in spatiotemporal gene regulation in animals. The evolutionarily conserved CCCTC-binding factor (CTCF) is required for insulator function in mammals, but not all of its binding sites act as insulators. Here we explore the sequence requirements of CTCF-mediated transcriptional insulation using a sensitive insulator reporter in mouse embryonic stem cells. We find that insulation potency depends on the number of CTCF-binding sites in tandem. Furthermore, CTCF-mediated insulation is dependent on upstream flanking sequences at its binding sites. CTCF-binding sites at topologically associating domain boundaries are more likely to function as insulators than those outside topologically associating domain boundaries, independently of binding strength. We demonstrate that insulators form local chromatin domain boundaries and weaken enhancer–promoter contacts. Taken together, our results provide genetic, molecular and structural evidence connecting chromatin topology to the action of insulators in the mammalian genome.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>17 May 2021</pubDate>
  </item>
  

</channel>
</rss>



