<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>
  
    <item>
	  <title>
		  The 4D Nucleome Data Portal as a resource for searching and visualizing curated nucleomics data</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-29697-4]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_comm.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Sarah B. Reiff, Andrew J. Schroeder, Koray Kirli, Andrea Cosolo, Clara Bakker, Soohyun Lee, Alexander D. Veit, Alexander K. Balashov, Carl Vitzthum, William Ronchetti, Kent M. Pitman, Jeremy Johnson, Shannon R. Ehmsen, Peter Kerpedjiev, Nezar Abdennur, Maxim Imakaev, Serkan Utku Öztürk, Uğur Çamoğlu, Leonid A. Mirny, Nils Gehlenborg, Burak H. Alver, Peter J. Park </p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The 4D Nucleome (4DN) Network aims to elucidate the complex structure and organization of chromosomes in the nucleus and the impact of their disruption in disease biology. We present the 4DN Data Portal (https://data.4dnucleome.org/), a repository for datasets generated in the 4DN network and relevant external datasets. Datasets were generated with a wide range of experiments, including chromosome conformation capture assays such as Hi-C and other innovative sequencing and microscopy-based assays probing chromosome architecture. All together, the 4DN data portal hosts more than 1800 experiment sets and 36000 files. Results of sequencing-based assays from different laboratories are uniformly processed and quality-controlled. The portal interface allows easy browsing, filtering, and bulk downloads, and the integrated HiGlass genome browser allows interactive visualization and comparison of multiple datasets. The 4DN data portal represents a primary resource for chromosome contact and other nuclear architecture data for the scientific community.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>2 May 2022</pubDate>
  </item>


    <item>
	  <title>
		  Chromatin interaction-aware gene regulatory modeling with graph attention networks</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://genome.cshlp.org/content/32/5/930.long]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/genome_research.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Alireza Karbalayghareh, Merve Sahin, Christina S. Leslie</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Linking distal enhancers to genes and modeling their impact on target gene expression are longstanding unresolved problems in regulatory genomics and critical for interpreting noncoding genetic variation. Here, we present a new deep learning approach called GraphReg that exploits 3D interactions from chromosome conformation capture assays to predict gene expression from 1D epigenomic data or genomic DNA sequence. By using graph attention networks to exploit the connectivity of distal elements up to 2 Mb away in the genome, GraphReg more faithfully models gene regulation and more accurately predicts gene expression levels than the state-of-the-art deep learning methods for this task. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>1 May 2022</pubDate>
  </item>


    <item>
	  <title>
		  Transcriptional coupling of distant regulatory genes in living embryos</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04680-7]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Michal Levo, João Raimundo, Xin Yang Bing, Zachary Sisco, Philippe J. Batut, Sergey Ryabichko, Thomas Gregor, Michael S. Levine</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The prevailing view of metazoan gene regulation is that individual genes are independently regulated by their own dedicated sets of transcriptional enhancers. Past studies have reported long-range gene–gene associations1,2,3, but their functional importance in regulating transcription remains unclear. Here we used quantitative single-cell live imaging methods to provide a demonstration of co-dependent transcriptional dynamics of genes separated by large genomic distances in living Drosophila embryos. We find extensive physical and functional associations of distant paralogous genes, including co-regulation by shared enhancers and co-transcriptional initiation over distances of nearly 250 kilobases. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>4 May 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

  
  	<item>
	  <title>
		  DNA tension-modulated translocation and loop extrusion by SMC complexes revealed by molecular dynamics simulations</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/50/9/4974/6574674?login=false]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/oxford.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Stefanos K Nomidis, Enrico Carlon, Stephan Gruber, John F Marko</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Structural Maintenance of Chromosomes (SMC) complexes play essential roles in genome organization across all domains of life. To determine how the activities of these large (≈50 nm) complexes are controlled by ATP binding and hydrolysis, we developed a molecular dynamics model that accounts for conformational motions of the SMC and DNA. The model combines DNA loop capture with an ATP-induced 'power stroke' to translocate the SMC complex along DNA. This process is sensitive to DNA tension: at low tension (0.1 pN), the model makes loop-capture steps of average 60 nm and up to 200 nm along DNA (larger than the complex itself), while at higher tension, a distinct inchworm-like translocation mode appears. By tethering DNA to an experimentally-observed additional binding site ('safety belt'), the model SMC complex can perform loop extrusion (LE). [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>20 May 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

  	<item>
	  <title>
		  The Impact of Space and Time on the Functional Output of the Genome</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://cshperspectives.cshlp.org/content/14/4/a040378.long]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/csh.jpeg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Marcelo Nollmann, Isma Bennabi, Markus Götz, Thomas Grego</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Over the past two decades, it has become clear that the multiscale spatial and temporal organization of the genome has important implications for nuclear function. This review centers on insights gained from recent advances in light microscopy on our understanding of transcription. We discuss spatial and temporal aspects that shape nuclear order and their consequences on regulatory components, focusing on genomic scales most relevant to function. The emerging picture is that spatiotemporal constraints increase the complexity in transcriptional regulation, highlighting new challenges, such as uncertainty about how information travels from molecular factors through the genome and space to generate a functional output. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>17 May 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

    	<item>
	  <title>
		  NANOG prion-like assembly mediates DNA bridging to facilitate chromatin reorganization and activation of pluripotency</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41556-022-00896-x]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_cell_bio.jpeg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Kyoung-Jae Choi, My Diem Quan, Chuangye Qi, Joo-Hyung Lee, Phoebe S. Tsoi, Mahla Zahabiyon, Aleksandar Bajic, Liya Hu, B. V. Venkataram Prasad, Shih-Chu Jeff Liao, Wenbo Li, Allan Chris M. Ferreon, Josephine C. Ferreon</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Human NANOG expression resets stem cells to ground-state pluripotency. Here we identify the unique features of human NANOG that relate to its dose-sensitive function as a master transcription factor. NANOG is largely disordered, with a C-terminal prion-like domain that phase-transitions to gel-like condensates. Full-length NANOG readily forms higher-order oligomers at low nanomolar concentrations, orders of magnitude lower than typical amyloids. Using single-molecule Förster resonance energy transfer and fluorescence cross-correlation techniques, we show that NANOG oligomerization is essential for bridging DNA elements in vitro. Using chromatin immunoprecipitation sequencing and Hi-C 3.0 in cells, we validate that NANOG prion-like domain assembly is essential for specific DNA recognition and distant chromatin interactions. Our results provide a physical basis for the indispensable role of NANOG in shaping the pluripotent genome. NANOG’s unique ability to form prion-like assemblies could provide a cooperative and concerted DNA bridging mechanism that is essential for chromatin reorganization and dose-sensitive activation of ground-state pluripotency. </p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>24 May 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

  

</channel>
</rss>



