<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>
  
    <item>
	  <title>
		  Cell type determination for cardiac differentiation occurs soon after seeding of human-induced pluripotent stem cells</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8985385/]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/genome_biology.jpeg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Connie L. Jiang, Yogesh Goyal, Naveen Jain, Qiaohong Wang, Rachel E. Truitt, Allison J. Coté, Benjamin Emert, Ian A. Mellis, Karun Kiani, Wenli Yang, Rajan Jain, Arjun Raj</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Cardiac differentiation of human-induced pluripotent stem (hiPS) cells consistently produces a mixed population of cardiomyocytes and non-cardiac cell types, even when using well-characterized protocols. We sought to determine whether different cell types might result from intrinsic differences in hiPS cells prior to the onset of differentiation. Altogether, our results show that while substantial heterogeneity exists in the initial hiPS cell population, it is not responsible for the variability observed in differentiated outcomes; instead, factors specifying the various cell types likely act during a window that begins shortly after the seeding of hiPS cells for differentiation.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>5 Apr 2022</pubDate>
  </item>


    <item>
	  <title>
		  Cohesin-dependence of neuronal gene expression relates to chromatin loop length</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://elifesciences.org/articles/76539]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/elife.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Lesly Calderon, Felix D Weiss, Jonathan A Beagan, Marta S Oliveira, Radina Georgieva, Yi-Fang Wang, Thomas S Carroll, Gopuraja Dharmalingam, Wanfeng Gong, Kyoko Tossell, Vincenzo de Paola, Chad Whilding, Mark A Ungless, Amanda G Fisher, Jennifer E Phillips-Cremins, Matthias Merkenschlager</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Cohesin and CTCF are major drivers of 3D genome organization, but their role in neurons is still emerging. Here we show a prominent role for cohesin in the expression of genes that facilitate neuronal maturation and homeostasis. Unexpectedly, we observed two major classes of activity-regulated genes with distinct reliance on cohesin in mouse primary cortical neurons. Immediate early genes remained fully inducible by KCl and BDNF, and short-range enhancer-promoter contacts at the Immediate early gene Fos formed robustly in the absence of cohesin. In contrast, cohesin was required for full expression of a subset of secondary response genes characterised by long-range chromatin contacts.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>26 Apr 2022</pubDate>
  </item>


    <item>
	  <title>
		  Multiplexed genome regulation in vivo with hyper-efficient Cas12a</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41556-022-00870-7]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_cell_bio.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Lucie Y. Guo, Jing Bian, Alexander E. Davis, Pingting Liu, Hannah R. Kempton, Xiaowei Zhang, Augustine Chemparathy, Baokun Gu, Xueqiu Lin, Draven A. Rane, Xiaoshu Xu, Ryan M. Jamiolkowski, Yang Hu, Sui Wang, Lei S. Qi </p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Multiplexed modulation of endogenous genes is crucial for sophisticated gene therapy and cell engineering. CRISPR–Cas12a systems enable versatile multiple-genomic-loci targeting by processing numerous CRISPR RNAs (crRNAs) from a single transcript; however, their low efficiency has hindered in vivo applications. Through structure-guided protein engineering, we developed a hyper-efficient Lachnospiraceae bacterium Cas12a variant, termed hyperCas12a, with its catalytically dead version hyperdCas12a showing significantly enhanced efficacy for gene activation, particularly at low concentrations of crRNA.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>12 Apr 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

  
  	<item>
	  <title>
		  Modular and mechanistic changes across stages of colorectal cancer</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9022252/]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/bmc-cancer.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Sara Rahiminejad, Mano R. Maurya, Kavitha Mukund, Shankar Subramaniam</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">While mechanisms contributing to the progression and metastasis of colorectal cancer (CRC) are well studied, cancer stage-specific mechanisms have been less comprehensively explored. This is the focus of this manuscript. Here, we report molecular and modular networks for various stages of CRC, providing a pseudo-temporal view of the mechanistic changes associated with the disease. Our analysis highlighted similarities at both functional and topological levels, across stages. We further identified stage-specific mechanisms and biomarkers potentially contributing to the progression of CRC.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>21 Apr 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

  	<item>
	  <title>
		  WashU Epigenome Browser update 2022</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://academic.oup.com/nar/advance-article/doi/10.1093/nar/gkac238/6567479?login=true]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/oxford.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Daofeng Li, Deepak Purushotham, Jessica K Harrison, Silas Hsu, Xiaoyu Zhuo, Changxu Fan, Shane Liu, Vincent Xu, Samuel Chen, Jason Xu, Shinyi Ouyang, Angela S Wu, Ting Wang</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">WashU Epigenome Browser (https://epigenomegateway.wustl.edu/browser/) is a web-based genomic data exploration tool that provides visualization, integration, and analysis of epigenomic datasets. The newly renovated user interface and functions have enabled researchers to engage with the browser and genomic data more efficiently and effectively since 2018. Here, we introduce a new integrated panel design in the browser that allows users to interact with 1D (genomic features), 2D (such as Hi-C), 3D (genome structure), and 4D (time series) data in a single web page</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>12 Apr 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

  

</channel>
</rss>



