<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>
  
    	<item>
	  <title>
		  Stripenn detects architectural stripes from chromatin conformation data using computer vision</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-29258-9]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_comm.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Sora Yoon, Aditi Chandra, Golnaz Vahedi </p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Architectural stripes tend to form at genomic regions harboring genes with salient roles in cell identity and function. Therefore, the accurate identification and quantification of these features are essential for understanding lineage-specific gene regulation. Here, we present Stripenn, an algorithm rooted in computer vision to systematically detect and quantitate architectural stripes from chromatin conformation measurements using various technologies. We demonstrate that Stripenn outperforms existing methods and highlight its biological applications in the context of B and T lymphocytes. By comparing stripes across distinct cell types and different species, we find that these chromatin features are highly conserved and form at genes with prominent roles in cell-type-specific processes. In summary, Stripenn is a computational method that borrows concepts from widely used image processing techniques to demarcate and quantify architectural stripes.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>24 Mar 2022</pubDate>
  </item>


    <item>
	  <title>
		  Multi-color super-resolution imaging to study human coronavirus RNA during cellular infection</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2667237522000224?via%3Dihub]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/cell_reports_methods.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Jiarui Wang, Mengting Han, Anish R. Roy, Haifeng Wang, Leonhard Möckl, Leiping Zeng, W.E. Moerner, Lei S. Qi</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) is the third human coronavirus within 20 years that gave rise to a life-threatening disease and the first to reach pandemic spread. To make therapeutic headway against current and future coronaviruses, the biology of coronavirus RNA during infection must be precisely understood. Here, we present a robust and generalizable framework combining high-throughput confocal and super-resolution microscopy imaging to study coronavirus infection at the nanoscale. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>28 Feb 2022</pubDate>
  </item>


    <item>
	  <title>
		  Mitochondrial variant enrichment from high-throughput single-cell RNA sequencing resolves clonal populations</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41587-022-01210-8]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_biotech.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Tyler E. Miller, Caleb A. Lareau, Julia A. Verga, Erica A. K. DePasquale, Vincent Liu, Daniel Ssozi, Katalin Sandor, Yajie Yin, Leif S. Ludwig, Chadi A. El Farran, Duncan M. Morgan, Ansuman T. Satpathy, Gabriel K. Griffin, Andrew A. Lane, J. Christopher Love, Bradley E. Bernstein, Vijay G. Sankaran, Peter van Galen </p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The combination of single-cell transcriptomics with mitochondrial DNA variant detection can be used to establish lineage relationships in primary human cells, but current methods are not scalable to interrogate complex tissues. Here, we combine common 3′ single-cell RNA-sequencing protocols with mitochondrial transcriptome enrichment to increase coverage by more than 50-fold, enabling high-confidence mutation detection. The method successfully identifies skewed immune-cell expansions in primary human clonal hematopoiesis.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>24 Feb 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

  
  	<item>
	  <title>
		  HiCAR is a robust and sensitive method to analyze open-chromatin-associated genome organization</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.cell.com/molecular-cell/fulltext/S1097-2765(22)00098-3]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/molecular_cell.jpeg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Xiaolin Wei, Yu Xiang, Derek T. Peters, Choiselle Marius, Tongyu Sun, Ruocheng Shan, Jianhong Ou, Xin Lin, Feng Yue, Wei Li, Kevin W. Southerland, Yarui Diao</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The long-range interactions of cis-regulatory elements (cREs) play a central role in gene regulation. cREs can be characterized as accessible chromatin sequences. However, it remains technically challenging to comprehensively identify their spatial interactions. Here, we report a new method HiCAR (Hi-C on accessible regulatory DNA), which utilizes Tn5 transposase and chromatin proximity ligation, for the analysis of open-chromatin-anchored interactions with low-input cells. By applying HiCAR in human embryonic stem cells and lymphoblastoid cells, we demonstrate that HiCAR identifies high-resolution chromatin contacts with an efficiency comparable with that of in situ Hi-C over all distance ranges. Interestingly, we found that the “poised” gene promoters exhibit silencer-like function to repress the expression of distal genes via promoter-promoter interactions. Lastly, we applied HiCAR to 30,000 primary human muscle stem cells and demonstrated that HiCAR is capable of analyzing chromatin accessibility and looping using low-input primary cells and clinical samples.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>22 Feb 2022</pubDate>
  </item>



  

</channel>
</rss>



