<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>
  
    	<item>
	  <title>
		  Stripenn detects architectural stripes from chromatin conformation data using computer vision</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-29258-9]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_comm.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Sora Yoon, Aditi Chandra, Golnaz Vahedi </p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Architectural stripes tend to form at genomic regions harboring genes with salient roles in cell identity and function. Therefore, the accurate identification and quantification of these features are essential for understanding lineage-specific gene regulation. Here, we present Stripenn, an algorithm rooted in computer vision to systematically detect and quantitate architectural stripes from chromatin conformation measurements using various technologies. We demonstrate that Stripenn outperforms existing methods and highlight its biological applications in the context of B and T lymphocytes. By comparing stripes across distinct cell types and different species, we find that these chromatin features are highly conserved and form at genes with prominent roles in cell-type-specific processes. In summary, Stripenn is a computational method that borrows concepts from widely used image processing techniques to demarcate and quantify architectural stripes.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>24 Mar 2022</pubDate>
  </item>


    <item>
	  <title>
		  Polymer physics reveals a combinatorial code linking 3D chromatin architecture to 1D chromatin states</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.cell.com/cell-reports/fulltext/S2211-1247(22)00349-7]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/cell_reports_methods.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Andrea Esposito, Simona Bianco, Andrea M. Chiariello, Alex Abraham, Luca Fiorillo, Mattia Conte, Raffaele Campanile, Mario Nicodemi</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The mammalian genome has a complex, functional 3D organization. However, it remains largely unknown how DNA contacts are orchestrated by chromatin organizers. Here, we infer from only Hi-C the cell-type-spe- cific arrangement of DNA binding sites sufficient to recapitulate, through polymer physics, contact patterns genome wide. Our model is validated by its predictions in a set of duplications at Sox9 against available in- dependent data.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>29 Mar 2022</pubDate>
  </item>


    <item>
	  <title>
		  Innovative computational approaches shed light on genetic mechanisms underlying cognitive impairment among children born extremely preterm</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://jneurodevdisorders.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s11689-022-09429-x]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/springer_link.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Weifang Liu, Quan Sun, Le Huang, Arjun Bhattacharya, Geoffery W. Wang, Xianming Tan, Karl C. K. Kuban, Robert M. Joseph, T. Michael O'Shea, Rebecca C. Fry, Yun Li, Hudson P. Santos Jr</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Although survival rates for infants born extremely preterm (gestation < 28 weeks) have improved significantly in recent decades, neurodevelopmental impairment remains a major concern. Children born extremely preterm remain at high risk for cognitive impairment from early childhood to adulthood. However, there is limited evidence on genetic factors associated with cognitive impairment in this population. [...] We conducted a novel computational analysis by utilizing an LPA-inferred phenotype with genetics data for the first time. This study suggests that rs11829294 and its LD buddies have potential regulatory roles on genes that could impact neurocognitive impairment for extreme preterm born children.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>3 Mar 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

  
  	<item>
	  <title>
		  Non-cell-autonomous disruption of nuclear architecture as a potential cause of COVID-19-induced anosmia</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.cell.com/molecular-cell/fulltext/S1097-2765(22)00098-3]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/cell-press.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Marianna Zazhytska, Albana Kodra, Daisy A. Hoagland, Justin Frere, John F. Fullard, Hani Shayya, Natalie G. McArthur, Rasmus Moeller, Skyler Uhl Arina D. Omer,7 Max E. Gottesman, Stuart Firestein, Qizhi Gong, Peter D. Canoll, James E. Goldman, Panos Roussos, Benjamin R. tenOever, Jonathan B. Overdevest, Stavros Lomvardas</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">SARS-CoV-2 infects less than 1% of cells in the human body, yet it can cause severe damage in a variety of organs. Thus, deciphering the non-cell-autonomous effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection is imperative for understanding the cellular and molecular disruption it elicits. Neurological and cognitive defects are among the least understood symptoms of COVID-19 patients, with olfactory dysfunction being their most common sensory deficit. Here, we show that both in humans and hamsters, SARS-CoV-2 infection causes widespread downregulation of olfactory receptors (ORs) and of their signaling components.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>17 Mar 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

  	<item>
	  <title>
		  Systematic reconstruction of cellular trajectories across mouse embryogenesis</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41588-022-01018-x]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_genetics.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Chengxiang Qiu, Junyue Cao, Beth K. Martin, Tony Li, Ian C. Welsh, Sanjay Srivatsan, Xingfan Huang, Diego Calderon, William Stafford Noble, Christine M. Disteche, Stephen A. Murray, Malte Spielmann, Cecilia B. Moens, Cole Trapnell, Jay Shendure</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Mammalian embryogenesis is characterized by rapid cellular proliferation and diversification. Within a few weeks, a single-cell zygote gives rise to millions of cells expressing a panoply of molecular programs. Although intensively studied, a comprehensive delineation of the major cellular trajectories that comprise mammalian development in vivo remains elusive. Here, we set out to integrate several single-cell RNA-sequencing (scRNA-seq) datasets that collectively span mouse gastrulation and organogenesis, supplemented with new profiling of ~150,000 nuclei from approximately embryonic day 8.5 (E8.5) embryos staged in one-somite increments.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>14 Mar 2022</pubDate>
  </item>

  

</channel>
</rss>



