<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

  <title><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:18px; font-family:Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif; margin: 0 -10px;"><strong>Latest 4DN Publications</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/xmls/4DN_publications.xml"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/icons/Feed-icon.svg" style="height: 20px; float: right;"></a></p>]]></title>
  <link>https://www.4dnucleome.org/4dn-publications.html</link>
  <description>4D Nucleome Publications</description>
  
   <item>
	  <title>
		  Chromatin tracing and multiplexed imaging of nucleome architectures (MINA) and RNAs in single mammalian cells and tissue</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41596-021-00518-0]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_protocols.jpeg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Miao Liu, Bing Yang, Mengwei Hu, Jonathan S. D. Radda, Yanbo Chen, Shengyan Jin, Yubao Cheng, Siyuan Wang</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">The genome is hierarchically organized into several 3D architectures, including chromatin loops, domains, compartments and regions associated with nuclear lamina and nucleoli. Changes in these architectures have been associated with normal development, aging and a wide range of diseases. Despite its critical importance, understanding how the genome is spatially organized in single cells, how organization varies in different cell types in mammalian tissue and how organization affects gene expression remains a major challenge. Previous approaches have been limited by a lack of capacity to directly trace chromatin folding in 3D and to simultaneously measure genomic organization in relation to other nuclear components and gene expression in the same single cells. We have developed an image-based 3D genomics technique termed ‘chromatin tracing’, which enables direct 3D tracing of chromatin folding along individual chromosomes in single cells. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>26 Apr 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  Integrated spatial genomics reveals global architecture of single nuclei</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-03126-2]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Yodai Takei, Jina Yun, Shiwei Zheng, Noah Ollikainen, Nico Pierson, Jonathan White, Sheel Shah, Julian Thomassie, Shengbao Suo, Chee-Huat Linus Eng, Mitchell Guttman, Guo-Cheng Yuan, Long Cai</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Identifying the relationships between chromosome structures, nuclear bodies, chromatin states and gene expression is an overarching goal of nuclear-organization studies. Because individual cells appear to be highly variable at all these levels, it is essential to map different modalities in the same cells. Here we report the imaging of 3,660 chromosomal loci in single mouse embryonic stem (ES) cells using DNA seqFISH+, along with 17 chromatin marks and subnuclear structures by sequential immunofluorescence and the expression profile of 70 RNAs. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>27 Jan 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  SPIN reveals genome-wide landscape of nuclear compartmentalization</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://genomebiology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13059-020-02253-3]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/genome_biology.jpeg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Yuchuan Wang, Yang Zhang, Ruochi Zhang, Tom van Schaik, Liguo Zhang, Takayo Sasaki, Daniel Peric-Hupkes, Yu Chen, David M. Gilbert, Bas van Steensel, Andrew S. Belmont, Jian Ma</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">We report SPIN, an integrative computational method to reveal genome-wide intranuclear chromosome positioning and nuclear compartmentalization relative to multiple nuclear structures, which are pivotal for modulating genome function. As a proof-of-principle, we use SPIN to integrate nuclear compartment mapping (TSA-seq and DamID) and chromatin interaction data (Hi-C) from K562 cells to identify 10 spatial compartmentalization states genome-wide relative to nuclear speckles, lamina, and putative associations with nucleoli. These SPIN states show novel patterns of genome spatial organization and their relation to other 3D genome features and genome function (transcription and replication timing). SPIN provides critical insights into nuclear spatial and functional compartmentalization.</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>14 Jan 2021</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  TSA-seq reveals a largely conserved genome organization relative to nuclear speckles with small position changes tightly correlated with gene expression changes</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://genome.cshlp.org/content/early/2020/12/18/gr.266239.120]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/genome_research.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Liguo Zhang, Yang Zhang, Yu Chen, Omid Gholamalamdari, Yuchuan Wang, Jian Ma, Andrew S. Belmont</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">TSA-seq mapping suggests that gene distance to nuclear speckles is more deterministic and predictive of gene expression levels than gene radial positioning. Gene expression correlates inversely with distance to nuclear speckles, with chromosome regions of unusually high expression located at the apex of chromosome loops protruding from the nuclear periphery into the interior. Genomic distances to the nearest lamina-associated domain are larger for loop apexes mapping closest to nuclear speckles, suggesting the possibility of conservation of speckle-associated regions. To facilitate comparison of genome organization by TSA-seq, we reduced required cell numbers 10-20-fold for TSA-seq by deliberately saturating protein-labeling while preserving distance mapping by the still unsaturated DNA-labeling. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>17 Dec 2020</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  Close to the edge: Heterochromatin at the nucleolar and nuclear peripheries</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S1874939920302492]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/elsevier.png" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">Aizhan Bizhanova, Paul D. Kaufman</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Chromatin is a dynamic structure composed of DNA, RNA, and proteins, regulating storage and expression of the genetic material in the nucleus. Heterochromatin plays a crucial role in driving the three-dimensional arrangement of the interphase genome, and in preserving genome stability by maintaining a subset of the genome in a silent state. Spatial genome organization contributes to normal patterns of gene function and expression, and is therefore of broad interest. Mammalian heterochromatin, the focus of this review, mainly localizes at the nuclear periphery, forming Lamina-associated domains (LADs), and at the nucleolar periphery, forming Nucleolus-associated domains (NADs). [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>29 Nov 2020</pubDate>
  </item>

   <item>
	  <title>
		  Trans- and cis-acting effects of Firre on epigenetic features of the inactive X chromosome</title>
	  <link><![CDATA[https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-19879-3]]></link>
	  <description>
		  <![CDATA[<p style="font-size:11px; font-style:italic; margin: 5px 0; font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;"><img src="https://4dnucleome.org/Assets/images/nature_comm.jpg" align="left" height="70" width="70" style="margin:0 15px 15px 0;">He Fang, Giancarlo Bonora, Jordan P. Lewandowski, Jitendra Thakur, Galina N. Filippova, Steven Henikoff, Jay Shendure, Zhijun Duan, John L. Rinn, Xinxian Deng, William S. Noble, Christine M. Disteche</p>
			  <p style="font-family: Segoe, 'Segoe UI', 'DejaVu Sans', 'Trebuchet MS', Verdana, sans-serif;">Firre encodes a lncRNA involved in nuclear organization. Here, we show that Firre RNA expressed from the active X chromosome maintains histone H3K27me3 enrichment on the inactive X chromosome (Xi) in somatic cells. This trans-acting effect involves SUZ12, reflecting interactions between Firre RNA and components of the Polycomb repressive complexes. Without Firre RNA, H3K27me3 decreases on the Xi and the Xi-perinucleolar location is disrupted, possibly due to decreased CTCF binding on the Xi. [...]</p>]]></description>
	  <pubDate>27 Nov 2020</pubDate>
  </item>
  

</channel>
</rss>



